<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">     
    <channel>      
        <title>Voice of America</title>     
        <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com</link>
        <description><![CDATA[Voice of America is an international news and broadcast organization serving Central and Eastern Europe, the Caucasus, Central Asia, Russia, the Middle East and Balkan countries]]></description>
        <image>
            <url>http://www.voanews.com/img/voa/rssLogo_VOA.gif</url>
            <title>Voice of America</title>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com</link>
        </image>
        <language>en-US-LEARN</language>
        <copyright>2012 - VOA</copyright>   
        <ttl>60</ttl>        
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 13:21:20 +0000</lastBuildDate> 
        <generator>Pangea CMS – VOA</generator>        
        <atom:link href="http://learningenglish.voanews.com/api/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
            <title>UN Chief Wants 3,000 Troops Sent to Central African Republic</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


From VOA Learning English, this is In the News.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

United Nations Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon has appealed for international action to stop religious violence in the Central African Republic.&#160; Mr. Ban asked the Security Council on Thursday to deploy at least 3,000 more troops to the country within the coming days and weeks.&#160; He said, “When innocent civilians are being murdered in large numbers, deliberately targeted in the most brutal fashion, simply because of who they are, the world must act.”&#160;

&#160;

More than 7,000 African Union and French forces are already in the country.&#160; The European Union has promised to send another 1,000 soldiers.&#160; The Central African Republic is a former French colony.&#160;

&#160;

This week, Mr. Ban also proposed $38 million in financial and other aid for the AU forces.&#160; He worries the religious violence could turn into genocide.&#160; The unrest began a year ago after Muslim rebels ousted the president, Francois Bozize.&#160; His overthrow and resulting violence led to a majority Christian militia.&#160; Its members are accused of carrying out attacks against Muslim civilians.&#160; Since December, hundreds of people have died in clashes between Muslims and Christians.&#160; Tens of thousands have fled the country in the past month.&#160;

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

The militia men call themselves the anti-balaka.&#160; Balaka is said to be a word for knife or machete in a local language.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160; Militia members say they came to the capital, Bangui, in December to oust the government of Michel Djotodia, the country’s first Muslim president.&#160; But international forces have accused the anti-balaka of being the problem.&#160; They say its fighters are increasingly turning to attacking homes and businesses.

&#160;

Some fighters are only teenagers.&#160; They have set up roadblocks on country roads, carrying weapons and demanding money.&#160; French and African troops have used force to disarm them.&#160;

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

The anti-balaka has been described as a loose alliance, and several leaders claim to speak for the men.&#160; Joachim Kokate represented the militia at a meeting in January.&#160; He says it is time for justice.&#160; He says those organizing theft and extrajudicial killings should be targeted, and they should answer for their acts.

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Many anti-balaka fighters tell VOA they want the same treatment the Muslim Seleka rebels are receiving.&#160; That means they want food, shelter and financial aid.&#160; They also want the chance to join the national army as part of a disarmament agreement.&#160;

&#160;

Some fighters consider themselves liberators of their country.&#160; Others see the conflict as becoming a battle between religious groups.&#160; But the militias are made up of both Christians and animists, people who believe that natural objects have spirits.&#160; They say they are motivated by nationalism -- not religion.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Anti-balaka leaders say they have tens of thousands of fighters.&#160;

&#160;

And that’s In the News from VOA Learning English.&#160; I’m Steve Ember.


]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/central-african-republic-ban-ki-moon/1856871.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/central-african-republic-ban-ki-moon/1856871.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 00:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>In the News</category>
            <comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/central-african-republic-ban-ki-moon/1856871.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments>
            <enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/838BFE12-87CB-4BEF-9889-FDDE26B066EA_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Gold Gains Importance in DRC Conflict</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Welcome to As It Is, from VOA Learning English!&#160; I’m Bob Doughty in Washington.&#160;

&#160;

Today on the program, some nations are attempting to cut links between the conflict in the Democratic Republic of Congo and eastern Congo’s mineral exports. &#160;Later in the show, we hear what Western governments are doing to avoid fueling the unrest.&#160;

&#160;

But first, researchers recently produced a map of mining areas in the Democratic Republic of Congo.&#160; The map shows mines under the control of the Congolese army and armed groups.&#160; The study suggests that the top “conflict mineral” in the area is now gold.&#160; Economics reporter Mario Ritter has more on the story.

&#160;

Gold Increases in Importance as a Conflict Mineral in DRC

&#160;

A Belgian group, the International Peace Information Service, carried out the study in partnership with the DRC registry of mines.

&#160;

The researchers found that armed groups were involved in about 200 of the 800 mines they studied.&#160; The Congolese army was involved at 265 mines.&#160; The researchers reported that both the military and the militias are taxing mine workers illegally.

&#160;

The International Peace Information Service carried out a similar survey in 2009.&#160; Filip Hilgert was the lead researcher.&#160; He told VOA the map they made four years ago is no longer correct.&#160; He said many of the miners are now digging for gold.&#160; And he said the armed groups are profiting much more from gold than from other conflict minerals, such as tin, tungsten and tantalum.&#160; These minerals are often called the “3Ts.”

&#160;

One reason for the change has been an increase in the price of gold.&#160; Another reason has been stronger international rules for mineral imports.&#160; The United States Congress passed legislation to fight the trade of conflict minerals.&#160; Mr. Hilgert says such efforts have had a big effect on trade in the 3Ts.&#160; But it has not affected the gold trade.

&#160;

Judith Sargentini is a member of the European Parliament.&#160; She has been campaigning for a European law on conflict minerals.&#160; She notes that gold, like diamonds, is easy to transport in small amounts.&#160; That explains why it is hard to know where it was mined.

&#160;

The German geological institute BGR has collected minerals from hundreds of mines in Rwanda.&#160; The collection could be used to prove whether a sample of minerals came from a conflict area.&#160; But, Judith Sargentini suggests that geophysical tests will not work.&#160; She says buyers need to know about their suppliers.

&#160;

“You cannot solve every trade in commodity by trying to find out what the geological background of a material is.&#160; It shows that you need, first of all, a due diligence supply chain, and second of all, initiatives that lead to fair trade gold mining.”

&#160;

Due diligence, in this case, means knowing and being able to trust your supplier.

&#160;

You are listening to As It Is from VOA Learning English.&#160; Thanks for joining us today.&#160; I’m Bob Doughty. &#160;&#160;

&#160;

Western Nations Act Against Conflict Minerals

&#160;

Western governments want to cut links between the conflict in the eastern Democratic Republic of Congo and the area’s mineral exports.&#160;

Both the United States and the European Union have taken steps to tighten control of mineral imports to avoid fueling the conflict in eastern Congo.&#160; Mario Ritter has more.

&#160;

The United States Congress passed the Dodd Frank Act in 2010.&#160; The law deals mainly with financial rules.&#160; But it also includes a special requirement for American-listed companies.&#160; It says buyers of tin, tantalum, tungsten or gold need to show they have not supported conflict in Africa’s Great Lakes area.

&#160;

Now the European Union is also writing a bill to prevent deals that help private armies in the eastern Congo.&#160; Judith Sargentini says the aim of the European law is to help break the link between the minerals trade and armed conflict.&#160; She suggests the law will require EU companies buying minerals to prove they were mined without supporting the conflict in the Congo.&#160;

&#160;

“We cannot just have the U.S. work on the issue, where we are the bigger trading countries with Africa and ignore this.&#160; It will influence European companies that want to trade on the U.S. market, but besides that, more importantly, Europe has a responsibility towards a lot of countries that are actually even former colonies.”

&#160;

She says the bill is not a reaction to an increase in Chinese imports of these minerals by companies that are not concerned about the Dodd Frank Act.&#160;

&#160;

“But I would say that European communication on trade and raw materials, of course, is completely influenced by the fear that Europe has that China will buy out everything and we don’t have anything in the future anymore”

&#160;

Judith Sargentini says the American law reduced trade and jobs.&#160; She notes that the proposed law will not stop imports from eastern Congo.&#160; She says some imports will continue even if the minerals were mined under what she called bad circumstances.&#160;

&#160;

Critics say the Dodd Frank Act stopped trade and led to the illegal transport of minerals through nearby countries.&#160; Ms. Sargentini agrees but says the planned law should have a different effect.&#160; She says the EU trade commissioner wants to increase trade with the Congo.&#160; She says the law will reward businesses that make an effort to trade minerals fairly and openly.&#160;

&#160;

Some Congolese experts say they think the Dodd Frank Act has helped to cut the flow of money to militia leaders.&#160; In eastern Congo, workers at the Enough Project say people have changed behaviors because of it, but the conflict minerals part of the law has yet to be enforced.&#160;

&#160;

And that is As It Is.&#160; I’m Bob Doughty.&#160; Be listening again tomorrow for another program from VOA Learning English.

&#160;

Keep listening to VOA for the latest world news coming up at the top of the hour, Universal Time.&#160; Thanks for spending part of your day with us.



]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/gold-conflict-minerals-drc/1854974.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/gold-conflict-minerals-drc/1854974.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 00:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>World</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/gold-conflict-minerals-drc/1854974.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/996C2DBA-9AF9-44CF-853F-DC963621412D_cx0_cy2_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Home Birth Movement Grows in the US </title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Welcome to American Mosaic from VOA Learning English.&#160;

&#160;

I’m June Simms.

&#160;

On the show today a report on an old and newly popular birthing practice.

&#160;

We also hear some great jazz from the past brought to new life in a Broadway musical.



Home Births in the US Becoming More Common

&#160;

Most births in the United States take place in hospitals.&#160; Women giving birth are under the care of doctors, armed with modern drugs and equipment.&#160; About one in three babies arrive through a surgical operation called a Caesarean section.&#160; However, a growing number of parents-to be are choosing a different way. Steve Ember reports.

&#160;

Emilie Jacobs and her husband, Rowan Finnegan, are preparing to welcome their second child.&#160; The baby will be born at their home --- just like their first child, 22-month-old Elias.&#160; The same nurse-midwife will help with this birth, too.&#160; If all goes well it will be a peaceful birth, without medicine, high tech machinery or surgery.

&#160;

“And then after giving birth, straight into my own shower, into my own bed, with our new family and our home.&#160; There’s just…there’s just nothing like that.”

&#160;

Emilie Jacobs attended medical school, so she has attended hospital births.&#160; She thinks doctors consider hospital rules and possible legal risks in administering birth care more than the needs of the women they serve.

&#160;

“It’s not an illness to be pregnant, it’s a beautiful experience, and if you feel supported and have the right kind of support, to labor and give birth in your own home is such a gift.”

&#160;

Home births have risen sharply in recent years.&#160; There are now about 30,000 such deliveries across the country each year. However, that number still represents less than one percent of all U.S. births.&#160;



A 2008 documentary, “The Business of Being Born,” helped increase the popularity of home births.&#160; The documentary included film of untroubled births in homes, including some in warm water.&#160; Other supporters of home birth have spread the idea with video of their water births with midwives assisting.

&#160;

Critics disagree about the safety of home births.&#160; One study found that babies born at home are ten times likelier to born dead.&#160; The study found that they are also four times more likely to have serious neurological problems.

&#160;

The findings were reported in the American Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology.&#160; Study co-author Dr. Jack Chervenak is with the New York-Presbyterian/Weill Cornell Medical Center.

&#160;

“We here on our labor and delivery unit fight for seconds when an unexpected fetal distress occurs, we do drills, so that we plan an emergency Caesarean and fight for seconds.&#160; If someone is as much as one block away from this hospital, it’s too far.”

&#160;

But others say the study had problems. &#160;Tina Johnson is with the American College of Nurse Midwives.

&#160;

“He used a lot of flawed data and drew a lot of conclusions that are inconsistent with all of the other research that’s out there currently, including another recent AJOG article, that came out more recently, citing that planned home births, with certified nurse-midwives, outcomes are just as safe as midwifery deliveries in the hospital.”

&#160;

Writer Jennifer Block agrees.&#160; She says women are choosing home birth for the baby’s health as well their own.

&#160;

“Because if the mother has a spontaneous vaginal birth, that’s absolutely the best-case scenario for a baby.&#160; We know babies benefit from vaginal birth: their lungs, their respiratory health, their gut health: they are colonized with good bacteria.”

&#160;

And Ms. Block notes that the experience is very different in Western Europe and some other countries.&#160; In those areas, midwives care for healthy pregnant women and send them to doctors only if there are problems or known risks.

&#160;

Broadway Show Honors Music of the Cotton Club




The Cotton Club in New York City helped bring fame to many African-American performers during the early 1920s to the 1940s.&#160; Now, a new musical play celebrates some of the greatest jazz musicians who played there.&#160; Bob Doughty has more on the show “After Midnight.”

&#160;

Two men partnered to create “After Midnight.”&#160; Wynton Marsalis is the artistic director of Jazz at Lincoln Center in New York City. &#160;His friend Jack Viertel is the director of a company that brings old musicals back to life in new shows.&#160; Their shared love of the music of this time gave birth to “After Midnight.”

&#160;

The Cotton Club was in the Harlem neighborhood of the city. David Levering Lewis is a history professor at New York University and writer of the book “When Harlem Was In Vogue.”&#160; He says “After Midnight” shows what one night at the famous nightclub was really like.

&#160;

&quot;I thought it captured the flavor of what would have been one night - the best ever - at the Cotton Club.&quot;

&#160;

Duke Ellington, Cab Calloway and Bessie Smith are just some of the musicians re-created in “After Midnight.”&#160; Mr. Viertel and Mr. Marsalis used old sound recordings from the Cotton Club to re-create what it was really like.

&#160;

&quot;Hello Everybody!&#160; Welcome to our famous Cotton Club.&#160; It’s great to see so many friends here tonight, enjoying themselves in spite of the cover charge.&#160; If you can spare a minute from your merry making, I’d like to have the pleasure of introducing the greatest living master of jungle music, the rip-roaring harmony hound, none other than Duke Ellington!&quot;

&#160;

But there is an ugly side to the history.&#160; The Cotton Club was located in the center of the African-American neighborhood of Harlem. The club used black performers. &#160;But the club only permitted white people to attend the shows.

&#160;

Mr. Lewis describes how even the celebrated composer W.C. Handy was not permitted to enter.&#160;&#160;

&#160;

&quot;As everyone knows, it was infamously racially-exclusive.&#160; W.C. Handy wished to go one evening to The Cotton Club and he was turned away.&#160; And he could hear his music being performed!&quot;

&#160;

Cotton Club shows often presented African-Americans in insulting ways.&#160; But this is not explored in “After Midnight.”&#160; Mr. Viertel says the creators wanted to free the music from its past.&#160;&#160;&#160;

&#160;

I’m June Simms. Our program was Anna Matteo and John Abbott. Caty Weaver was the producer

&#160;

Do you have a question about American life, people or places? Send an e-mail to learningenglish@voanews.com. We might answer your question in a future show. You can also visit our website at learningenglish.voanews.com to find transcripts and audio of our shows.

&#160;

Join us again next week for American Mosaic from VOA Learning English.





]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/article/1855957.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/article/1855957.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>USA</category><category>American Mosaic</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/article/1855957.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/3620C1C5-8655-49E5-BEDE-AE833FF34C19_cx0_cy32_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Syrian Refugees in Lebanon Lack Food Aid and Education</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


From VOA Learning English, this is As It Is.

&#160;

Welcome back.&#160; I’m Caty Weaver.&#160; On the program today we explore the situation of almost one million Syrian refugees currently living in Lebanon.&#160; More and more flee across the border every day. &#160;The United Nations is concerned about the limited food aid it can provide the refugees. &#160;And it says most refugee children are receiving little or no education.

&#160;

The Syrian refugee crisis in Lebanon: today on As It Is.



Many Syrian Refugees in Lebanon Lose Food Aid

&#160;

United Nations agencies have been forced to reduce food aid to about one out of five Syrian refugees in Lebanon. &#160;Those who get no food say they are falling into deep debt.&#160; VOA reporter Jamie Detmer investigated the situation from Beirut. &#160;Christopher Cruise has his report.

&#160;

Syrian refugees continue to flee the violence in their country.&#160; Many of them are going to Lebanon. &#160;U.N. aid agencies found it increasingly difficult to provide food assistance to them for most of last year.&#160; Twenty percent of registered refugees had their food aid ended at the end of 2013.

&#160;

Um-Odai fled the Syrian city of Homs with her husband and five children. &#160;They are living in a shelter in the northern Lebanese city of Tripoli.

&#160;

She says her family stopped receiving assistance, and now, they owe a lot of money.&#160; Her husband is too sick to look for work. &#160;Four of her children are very young.&#160; Her oldest son has a wife and a newborn.

&#160;&#160;

She says one of her sons works as a laborer on jobs that sometimes last for just one day.&#160; When he finds a job he can bring money to the family. &#160;But Um-Odai says the family owes money to many shops in the area. &#160;They do not know how they will pay their debt.

&#160;

She says they owe $2,000 after living in Lebanon for a year-and-half.

&#160;

About eleven thousand Syrian refugees arrive in Lebanon every week.&#160; Negotiators have made little progress in reaching an agreement to end the civil war in Syria.&#160; The flow of Syrian refugees to Lebanon shows no sign of slowing.&#160; A million Syrians will have registered as refugees in Lebanon by the beginning of March if new arrivals continue at the current rate.

&#160;

Ninette Kelley is the head of the U.N. refugee agency in Lebanon. &#160;She says the U.N. does not have enough food for all of the refugees, so it helps those most at risk.&#160;

&#160;

“Most of last year, blanket food assistance was provided to everybody who was registered, but this is not something that is a normal practice.&#160; But once you have more information you can further target your provision of food assistance according to vulnerability.”

&#160;

Last year, U.N. agencies worked to establish who were the most at risk among all registered Syrian refugees.&#160; The agencies found 80 percent of the refugees would have no other form of food support without international assistance. The agencies used this information to make some difficult decisions.

&#160;

“Which meant that there were 20 percent who had been receiving food who were notified that they would no longer receive it on a regular basis.”

&#160;

But Um-Odai says she does not understand why she and her family are among about 250,000 refugees without food assistance.&#160; She says the decision does not seem reasonable. &#160;She says she and her husband know other refugees in the camp who are in the same situation as they are.&#160; But, she says, those refugees are still receiving U.N. money to buy food and her family is not.

&#160;

Even those who receive U.N. food aid say life is getting harder and more costly.&#160; They say they, too, are creating debt.

&#160;

I’m Christopher Cruise.

&#160;

United Nations officials say one-third of the Syrian refugees fleeing to Lebanon are school-age children.&#160; But the majority of them are not able to go to school.&#160; We return to Caty Weaver, who has more on the situation of these young refugees.

&#160;

Many Syrian Refugee Children Not Attending School




Eleven-year-old Marah has been in Lebanon for eighteen months.&#160; She lives in an unofficial refugee settlement near the coastal Lebanese city of Tripoli.&#160; Her family had lived on a farm near the Syrian city of Homs.&#160; They fled when a rocket hit their farmhouse during an attack.

&#160;

Marah is luckier than most of the refugee children in Lebanon: she is attending school.

&#160;

Marah says it is difficult for her to learn in Lebanon’s French-based educational program. &#160;In Syria, she was taught in Arabic.&#160; She says she speaks Lebanese to understand the other students. &#160;But there are problems.&#160; She says they sometimes insult her and other Syrian students for being refugees.

&#160;

But Marah at least has a chance of reaching her goal to become a nurse. &#160;In her settlement there are about 200 families.&#160; Only a few of them have children in school.

&#160;

Media reports about the refugees are mostly about their emergency needs -- like food and medical care. &#160;Those needs take most of the humanitarian aid as well. &#160;But the longer-term needs of the refugees are becoming more central as the Syrian civil war continues.&#160;

&#160;

The lack of educational possibilities for refugee children is a major concern for Ninette Kelley.

&#160;

“The situation of children is rather dire. &#160;There are over 300,000 now, Syrian school-age children, which is the same number of Lebanese children who were registered at Lebanese schools last year. &#160;And while the ministry of education has indicated they could absorb 100,000 in the formal education system that still leaves over 200,000 kids without a formal education option.”

&#160;

The U.N. and non-governmental groups are working together to try to provide basic reading and writing classes for children. They are centering efforts on the temporary refugee settlements that are being created. The Lebanese government has refused permission for the building of official refugee camps.

&#160;

But, Ms. Kelley says basic reading and writing classes are not going to meet the needs of older children in the camps.

&#160;

And that’s As It Is for today.&#160; I’m Caty Weaver.&#160; Thanks for joining us.


]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/syrian-refugees-lebanon-food-education-children/1855222.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/syrian-refugees-lebanon-food-education-children/1855222.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/syrian-refugees-lebanon-food-education-children/1855222.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/0F47B0C2-4A60-4A63-A6EF-D20DAC8C61DA_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Andrew Jackson and the Election of 1828</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


From VOA Learning English, welcome to The Making of a Nation, our weekly program of American history for people learning English. I’m Steve Ember.



This week in our series, we talk about the election of 1828. It was bitter and full of angry words and accusations.



The old Republican Party of Thomas Jefferson had split into two opposing groups. President John Quincy Adams led one of the groups. It called itself the National Republican Party.




Andrew Jackson, a military hero and politician, led the other group. It called itself the Democratic Party.



Each party had its own newspapers. In Washington, the Daily National Journal supported President Adams. The United States Telegraph supported General Jackson.



The Telegraph published accusations by Democrats in Congress against the administration.



The Journal, in turn, published a pamphlet that said Jackson had fought a man, chased him away like a dog and then stolen his wife.



Jackson denied these claims. Historians still do not know how much of this story is true. But the story had a great effect on Jackson for the rest of his life.



Jackson met the young woman, Rachel, at her mother&#39;s home near Nashville, Tennessee. Rachel and her husband, Lewis Robards, were living there at the time. They were having marriage problems. Robards argued with his wife about Jackson. He said she and Jackson seemed too close.



Robards reportedly wanted to fight Jackson with his fists. Jackson said he would face Robards not in a fistfight but in a gunfight, if Robards wished to fight like a gentleman. Robards rejected the invitation to a duel, and nothing more happened between the two men.



Robards and his wife settled their differences. But a short time later, they had another dispute, and Rachel left. Court records said she left with a man — Andrew Jackson.



Rachel&#39;s family said she told Robards she wanted a divorce. They said he threatened her, telling her he would carry her away by force.



So Rachel’s family said she decided to flee. She decided to go with some traders to Natchez, in the dangerous Mississippi territory.




By now, Rachel meant a great deal to Andrew Jackson. He had fallen in love with her. When the traders asked him to go with them to Natchez to protect them, he agreed. The group left for the territory early in 1791.



For his part, Lewis Robards began preparations for a divorce. He allowed Rachel’s family to believe that he and Rachel were no longer married. But, in fact, he did not complete the necessary legal action to make the divorce final.



Jackson returned from Natchez after several months. His opponents later claimed that he had married Rachel while in Natchez. They said she was still another man’s wife at the time. Opponents said the couple’s relationship was both immoral and illegal. They said Jackson was an adulterer for having a relationship with a married woman. And they said Rachel was a bigamist for having two husbands.



But Jackson said he believed Rachel and her first husband, Lewis Robards, were divorced. He said he returned to Nashville to ask Rachel’s mother for permission to marry her daughter and that she agreed.



Andrew and Rachel Jackson remained in Tennessee. The next two years were busy for Jackson. As a young lawyer, he worked hard and traveled far.



Then, in December 1793, Jackson said he discovered court papers showing that Lewis Robards had only recently divorced Rachel. Jackson said he was shocked. As soon as possible, he and Rachel were married again — legally this time.



Almost 10 years passed. Jackson became a judge and got involved in Tennessee politics. But the circumstances of his marriage remained an issue that led to arguments. For instance, a man once accused Jackson of cheating on a horse racing bet. Then the man called his wife a bigamist. Jackson killed the man in a duel.



Later, in the 1828 presidential election, Jackson’s opponents made Rachel’s honor a campaign issue. Jackson could not duel everyone who questioned his wife’s honor. So he asked a special committee of citizens to investigate his marriage and make a public report. Many people on the committee were his friends or supporters.



The committee found that the Jacksons were not at fault for getting married before Rachel and her first husband were legally divorced.



The pro-Jackson newspaper in Washington published the committee&#39;s report. Pro-Jackson papers also began to print vicious stories about President Adams and his wife.



Anti-Jackson newspapers did not publish the committee’s report. They continued to denounce the Jacksons’ marriage.



Historian Daniel Feller at the University of Tennessee is an expert on Andrew Jackson. He says the charges about Jackson’s marriage made a good story for people to talk about. But he says other accusations were more serious. These were about Jackson’s career.



“The attacks that really hit home were about Jackson’s unauthorized, and perhaps directly-against-orders, conquest of Florida in 1819. His sometimes savage disciplinary measures against his own troops. His declaring martial law in New Orleans and maintaining martial law in New Orleans and arresting people in New Orleans well after the War of 1812 was actually over.”&#160;



All during the bitter election campaign, neither Jackson nor his opponent, President Adams, said anything about one very important issue: slavery. Adams did not want to lose what little support he had in the South and West by denouncing slavery. Jackson did not want to lose the support of some Republicans in the North by openly defending it.



Adams&#39;s silence did not mean that he approved of slavery. Southerners were sure that he opposed it. And Jackson did not have to tell the South what he thought about slavery. He was a slave owner, and he had bought and sold slaves all his life.



There was another important difference between the two men and their political parties. President Adams and the Republicans represented the interests of those who owned property.



Many of the president&#39;s supporters felt that wealthy, property-owning citizens should control the government.



Jackson and the Democrats represented the interests of the common people. They did not feel that the rich had more right to govern than the poor.



The presidential election of 1828 was held on different days in the different states between October 31 and November 5. Voters in the northern states supported John Quincy Adams. Andrew Jackson won the South. Historian Daniel Feller says Southerners did not seem bothered by opponents’ fears that Jackson was mentally unstable and believed he should have unlimited power.



“They were much more compelled by the image of this great man of the people — exactly why they thought that is not clear — but, this great man of the people and also this great man on horseback, the Hero of New Orleans.”



Even President Adams recognized that Jackson was extremely well-liked.



“John Quincy Adams wrote in his diary years before the election that in a popularity contest, in a political contest, no man could stand against the Hero of New Orleans.”



When the electoral votes were counted, Andrew Jackson received 178. President Adams received only 83.



Rachel Jackson was proud of her husband. But she was not happy about the life she would have to lead as first lady. And her health seemed to be suffering. “For Mr. Jackson&#39;s sake,&quot; she said, &quot;I am glad. For my own part, I never wished it.&quot;



Nevertheless, the couple prepared to move to Washington. There was little time for Rachel to rest.



Then, just a few days before the Jacksons were to move, two doctors were called to the Jackson home. They found Rachel in great pain. She seemed to be having a heart attack.



After a day or so, she appeared to be better. She was able to sit up and talk with friends. But her mind was still troubled about the years ahead in Washington. &quot;I had rather be a doorkeeper in the house of God,&quot; she said, &quot;than to dwell in that palace in Washington.&quot;



In December of 1828, a few nights before Christmas, Rachel was sitting in a chair. Her husband had already gone to sleep. Suddenly, Rachel cried out and fell to the floor. The servants screamed. Jackson ran to the room, picked Rachel up and carried her to the bed. But he could see that life had already left her.



Witnesses said Jackson continued to sit next to her, holding his head in his hands.



Rachel was buried two days later. Ten thousand people went to the funeral. The Reverend William Hume spoke of Rachel Jackson&#39;s life. He talked of her kindness and humility. And he told how she had been upset about the personal accusations against her during the election campaign.



Jackson believed those accusations were a cause of Rachel&#39;s death. His anger is expressed on the stone above Rachel’s grave. One line of the inscription says, “A being so gentle and so virtuous, slander might wound but could not dishonor.”



At that time, Andrew Jackson was 61 years old. He was a tall, thin man. His long face was wrinkled. Most portraits of him show a great mass of messy hair pushed back from his high forehead. &#160;



Jackson&#39;s health had never really been good. He carried in his body two bullets from duels fought years before. But he was a tough man with a spirit strong enough to keep moving, even when he was grieving.



He left for Washington, DC in January 1829. A huge crowd was gathering there to greet him. They would create one of the wildest inaugural celebrations in American history.



And that will be our story next week.



I’m Steve Ember, inviting you to join next time for The Making of a Nation — American history from VOA Learning English.











]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/andrew-jackson-rachel-1828-election-john-quincy-adams/1742793.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/andrew-jackson-rachel-1828-election-john-quincy-adams/1742793.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>The Making of a Nation</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/andrew-jackson-rachel-1828-election-john-quincy-adams/1742793.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/86A25589-E71A-4809-8D13-03521D24184A_cx0_cy10_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Mosquitoes and Bats May Carry Disease</title>
            <description><![CDATA[&#160;




Hello and welcome to another program designed to help you learn and improve your American English.&#160; I’m Jim Tedder in Washington.&#160; Today we are concerned with your health.&#160; We have information about a disease that seems to have spread from Africa and Asia into the Western Hemisphere.&#160; If you have mosquitoes near your home, you will need to listen carefully.

&#160;

Then imagine you are sitting outside near the end of another day.&#160; Every now and then you see something fly above your house very quickly, and make sharp turns.&#160; No, it is not a bird.&#160; It is a bat, and it, too, may be a serious disease carrier.

&#160;

What are these illnesses?&#160; And how can you protect yourself from them?&#160; We’ll have the answers, next on As It Is.

&#160;

Mosquito&#39;s bite pass new virus to people in the Western Hemisphere



A painful disease found mainly in Africa and Asia has been discovered in the Western Hemisphere. &#160;The World Health Organization reported last December that two cases of chikungunya were found in the French part of the Caribbean island of Saint Martin.&#160; Since then, the disease has been reported on other islands in the Caribbean.

&#160;&#160;

Chikungunya results from a virus.&#160; It is passed to humans from the bite of an insect -- the mosquito.&#160; The disease can cause a higher than normal body temperature and pain in the head.&#160; It also causes pain in the joints, which can last for weeks. Chikunguya rarely kills people, but there is no treatment or vaccine for the disease. &#160;

&#160;

The WHO says chikungunya infected many people in the African nation of Gabon, India and islands in the Indian Ocean about 10 years ago. &#160;It spread within Europe for the first time in 2007.

&#160;

Peter Hotez is the head of the National School of Tropical Medicine at the Baylor College of Medicine in Texas. &#160;He says he soon expects to see reports of chikungunya in the southern United States.

&#160;

“The mosquitoes are here. &#160;That’s an important factor. &#160;Second, there may be some component of global warming.”

&#160;

He says insects carrying the disease are found in places where poverty and development are increasing, such as in the southern United States.

&#160;

Bats spread virus across Africa



Straw-colored fruit bats are found across much of Africa.&#160; The bats carry two deadly viruses that could spread to people. &#160;While scientists have long known this, they did not know until recently how many of the animals were carriers.

&#160;

A new study has found that one third of the fruit bats are infected with a virus similar to the one responsible for the viral disease rabies. &#160;And 42 percent carry henipaviruses, which can cause a deadly disease.

&#160;

The new study was a project of researchers with the University of Cambridge and the Zoological Society of London.&#160; The researchers studied blood and tissue from more than 2,000 bats from 12 African countries.&#160; They found the animals were genetically similar -- meaning they travel and live together across the continent. &#160;James Wood of the University of Cambridge says this genetic similarity helps speed the spread of the viruses.

&#160;

Fruit bats live in groups of more than 100,000.&#160; These groups often live near cities. In some areas, people hunt the animals for their meat. &#160;Eating bat meat can spread the viruses to humans. &#160;Henipaviruses can also be spread through contact with waste products from bats.




Neither disease has been reported in humans in Africa.&#160; But experts are warning that could change. &#160;Alison Peel helped to prepare a report on the study. &#160;She warns that trying to remove bats from cities could increase the risk of infection. &#160;In her words, “the most appropriate response is ongoing studies and public awareness to avoid handling bats, and to wash the wound thoroughly if you are bitten by a bat.”

&#160;

The report appeared in the journal Nature Communications.

&#160;

China reported death from influenza virus



In December, China reported the death of a woman who it said was the first human to become infected with a new kind of avian influenza virus. Researchers are working to learn more about the H10N8 strain of the virus that killed her. &#160;The World Health Organization says the speed at which China reported the case shows the country is getting better at identifying deadly viruses.&#160; The 73-year old woman died late last year, just six days after visiting a poultry market in Jiangxi Province.

&#160;

Bernhard Schwartlander is the WHO’s representative in China. &#160;He says the quick identification of the bird flu that killed the woman shows the increased strength of China’s surveillance system.

&#160;

“The fact that Chinese authorities detected this case in a 73-year-old woman that had other medical conditions actually shows that the active surveillance system, the active alert system, is actually working quite well.”

&#160;

The woman often visited markets were live chickens and other poultry were sold.

&#160;

She was taken to a hospital on November 30 and died December 6th. &#160;She had suffered from high blood pressure and heart disease, which may have kept her body from being able to fight the infection.&#160; Dr. Schwartlander says officials need to watch other people closely to see if the disease has spread.

&#160;

“Of course, we are always concerned when we see that the virus has actually jumped from one species to another. &#160;And you have to be very careful watching this because every time this happens it has, of course in theory, the potential for a wider spread.”

&#160;

Last year, about 100 people were infected with the H7N9 strain of bird flu. &#160;Chinese officials reacted quickly with increased testing and reporting of similar cases.

&#160;

The H10N8 virus had earlier been found in Guangdong Province and lived in poultry for many years. &#160;Dr. Schwartlander says the first human death from the virus is a worrisome development.

&#160;

“This is the first case that we detected the virus in a human being.”

&#160;

In 2002 and 2003, some countries criticized China for being slow to release news about Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome, also known as SARS. &#160;The disease killed more than 700 people. &#160;As health officials followed the disease, the government told reporters in China not to report on SARS. Government officials also did not tell WHO researchers much about the spread of the disease.

&#160;

Since then, China’s health systems have improved. &#160;But some experts say China must work harder to study laboratory-confirmed infections.

&#160;

Chinese officials are also closely watching for cases of the H5N1 bird flu virus, which has killed more than 380 people since 2003. &#160;Scientists fear the virus could change and then spread quickly from one person to another.



When it comes to your health, it is always better to know than not to know.&#160; There are more Learning English programs coming your way next, and world news at the beginning of the hour on VOA.&#160; I’m Jim Tedder in Washington.


]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/disease-mosquito-bat/1847845.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/disease-mosquito-bat/1847845.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Science &amp; Technology</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/disease-mosquito-bat/1847845.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/E6F3AD5C-0D0C-434D-8821-B42C5743F054_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>China and Taiwan Meet for Historic Talks</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Also, what could slow China&#39;s economy down this year | As It Is]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/china-taiwan-talks-economy/1851868.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/china-taiwan-talks-economy/1851868.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>World</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/china-taiwan-talks-economy/1851868.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/F9656F0A-DBCF-4B36-B34E-E0ACF4DE3271_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Snow Covers Much of the United States</title>
            <description><![CDATA[In December, snow fell in almost every state across the U.S. and resulted in the largest snow coverage since 2009. Weather experts say that snow may continue to fall in many areas through March.]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/weather-snow-storms/1852544.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/weather-snow-storms/1852544.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Science &amp; Technology</category><category>Science in the News</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/weather-snow-storms/1852544.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/6E5BB36F-8D46-4ACB-8CCA-1D54D8BC8B47_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Cambodia to Restart International Adoptions</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


This is As It Is.&#160; Thanks for joining us today.&#160; I’m June Simms in Washington.&#160;

&#160;

Today on the program, more and more Chinese couples are having babies by women in the United States.&#160; We tell why the practice is growing in popularity coming up later in the show.

&#160;

But first, Cambodia has announced plans to restart international adoptions this year.&#160; The move comes four years after the government suspended the practice after widespread reports of children being trafficked.&#160; Steve Ember has the story from VOA’s Robert Carmichael in Phnom Penh.

&#160;

Cambodia to Restart International Adoptions&#160;

&#160;

When it comes to international adoptions, Cambodia has had a poor record.&#160; For many years, local media reported many stories of poor parents being tricked into giving up their children.

&#160;

The children were being placed with foreign families, in exchange for thousands of dollars in so-called processing costs.&#160; Security checks were often not carried out on the people seeking to adopt.

&#160;

The situation was so bad that in 2001 several countries barred their citizens from adopting children from Cambodia.&#160; France, the United States and the United Kingdom were among those countries.

&#160;

The Hague Conference, or HCCH, is an international governmental organization that works to balance laws across national borders.&#160; In recent years, the group has joined with UNICEF to help the Cambodian government improve its adoption process.&#160;

&#160;

Laura Martinez-Mora is the group&#39;s main legal officer.&#160; She says Cambodia has made good progress.&#160; This includes passing a law on international adoptions and supporting legislation.&#160;

&#160;

She says workers are training local officials to make sure the parents have given their permission and that they fully understand what they have agreed to.

&#160;

“They have done so after being informed and counseled, and after having tried that they keep their child, so that there is information, they know what they are signing and even if they don&#39;t know how to read, they know what they are saying yes to.”

&#160;

Another issue is making sure the children have birth certificates.&#160; That is important in many countries, and a problem in Cambodia where less than 40 percent of children have one.&#160;

&#160;

“So we need to have essential safeguards to do inter-country adoptions as well as domestic adoptions.&#160; For example, to be sure that Child A is really Child A, that there is no problem with the birth certificate.&#160; Other types of issues like this need to be in place before any adoption takes place.&#160; So these are the things that Cambodia is working on now.”

&#160;

Under the terms of the 1993 Hague Adoption Convention, which Cambodia has signed, participating states are required to put the interests of the child first.&#160; The number one goal is to try to keep the child with their birth family or their extended family.

&#160;

If that is not possible, the next step is to try to find a home within the country.&#160; Experts want Cambodia to do more to support domestic adoption over the third and last possibility, which is international adoption.

&#160;

States must also put safety measures in place to prevent the kidnapping, sale and trafficking of children for adoption.&#160; And they must guarantee that there is no corruption in the process.&#160; That continues to be a major issue in Cambodia.&#160; Last year, Transparency International ranked the country as one of the 20 most corrupt in the world.

&#160;

UNICEF Cambodia&#39;s deputy representative, Sun Ah Kim, says several important measures still need to be in put in place.&#160; She says staff must receive the correct training.&#160; They have to make sure that the children are really in need of adoption.&#160; And, she says, they must also make sure the adopting parents are qualified.&#160;

&#160;

“As of now, not all these requirements are in place.&#160; The resumption of adoptions should take place gradually to guarantee the proper and orderly implementation of both the International Country Adoption Law and the Hague Convention.”

&#160;

The Ministry of Social Affairs says that 3,800 Cambodian children were adopted internationally between 1997 and 2009.&#160; That is the year Cambodia suspended adoptions.&#160; The recent announcement suggests that the country believes it is close to meeting the necessary requirements to begin again.&#160;

&#160;

I’m Steve Ember.

&#160;

You are listening to As It Is, from VOA Learning English.&#160; I’m June Simms in Washington.

&#160;

Chinese Couples Having Babies by American Moms

&#160;

More Chinese families are looking for surrogate mothers in the United States.&#160; A surrogate mother is a woman who agrees to become pregnant and carry a baby to full term for another woman who cannot have children.&#160; Surrogacy is illegal at most hospitals in China.&#160; But agencies are now connecting Chinese couples with Americans who will carry their children for a price.&#160;

&#160;

Tony Jiang and his wife Cherry live in Shanghai.&#160; The couple has three children, all born in the United States to an American surrogate mother.&#160; Their daughter and twins were born in California.




“The elder girl is now three years old.&#160; The younger twins are now 13 months.”

&#160;

The couple had twice tried surrogacy services in China through military hospitals, which can legally perform the operation. &#160;But their efforts were unsuccessful.&#160; They then contacted a surrogacy agency in the United States. &#160;There, they connected with Amanda, a California woman who wishes to use only her first name.&#160; She gave birth to all three of the Jiangs’ children.

&#160;

“Cherry was actually in the room with me when Nicole was born so she got to actually witness the birth and see Nicole come into this world.&#160; And she was so ecstatic, and she was crying, and she was just so happy.”

&#160;

China changed its one child policy last year.&#160; It now permits couples to have two children if one of the parents is an only child.&#160; This has led to an increase in the number of families seeking to have children. &#160;

&#160;

The Jiangs are among an increasing number of wealthy Chinese couples seeking to have babies by women in the United States.&#160; That decision comes with other values.&#160;

&#160;

Under the 14th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution, anyone born in the United States has a right to citizenship.&#160; U.S. citizens may also apply for green cards for their parents when they turn 21.

&#160;

Tony Jiang started an agency in Shanghai that works with Chinese couples who want to have children.&#160; He says most couples, like him and his wife, seek surrogate mothers because they are medically unable to have children themselves. &#160;They choose the United States because of the high quality of its health care system.

&#160;

“More and more patients are inquiring about services at clinics.”

&#160;

Surrogacy services can cost as much as $120,000.&#160; However, Chinese couples are increasingly willing to pay those high prices for the chance to have a child born in the United States.

&#160;

And that is As It Is, from VOA Learning English.&#160; I’m June Simms.&#160; Thanks for joining us.&#160; VOA world news is coming up at the beginning of the hour Universal Time.




]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/cambodia-international-adoptions-chinese-surrogates/1852002.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/cambodia-international-adoptions-chinese-surrogates/1852002.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>World</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/cambodia-international-adoptions-chinese-surrogates/1852002.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/A05A244D-C411-4885-833F-7434A70D6393_cx0_cy2_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Reporter and His Favorite Boots Travel the World</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Hello, and welcome to As It Is from VOA Learning English.

&#160;

I’m Christopher Cruise in Washington.

&#160;

Today on the program, VOA Reporter Steve Herman is here to tell us the story of the boots he has worn for almost 25 years as he has reported from around the world.&#160;



These are special boots:

&#160;

“I have worn them for up to 36 hours and they still felt good.&#160; They are the best-fitting boots I have ever owned.”

&#160;

But the boots are in bad condition.&#160;



Will Steve and his boots have to say goodbye?

&#160;

Longtime VOA Southeast Asia Correspondent Steve Herman visits today on As It Is.



The Story of a Reporter and His 25-Year-Old Boots



People who have to stand for a long time -- like soldiers, police officers and reporters -- need strong footwear that also feels good.&#160; VOA’s Steve Herman has been travelling the world with the same pair of boots for almost 25 years. But he has worn them so much that they may now be unwearable. &#160;Can they be saved?&#160; Here is Steve Herman to tell us the story of a man and his boots.

&#160;

Steve.

&#160;

Thanks, Chris.

&#160;

The story begins in Japan and moves to the city of Portland in the northwest American state of Oregon.&#160; The city is home of one of the last American shoe factories.

&#160;

The boots that star in this story are known as “Danner Lights.”&#160; I bought them at a store in Tokyo -- I think it was in 1991. &#160;The boots are leather and can be worn in the water.&#160; They keep your feet from getting wet.&#160; I have worn them for up to 36 hours and they still felt good.&#160; They are the best-fitting boots I have ever owned.&#160; I love my boots.

&#160;

They kept my feet dry as I crossed streams in Sichuan, China. &#160;I have worn them in the hot sands of the Middle East. &#160;They have been on my feet as I walked through wet, poisonous earth in Bhopal, India.&#160; I have worn them as I moved along the icy streets of Seoul, South Korea.&#160; They have helped keep me from falling as I looked out the open doors of military helicopters over wars.

&#160;

I have not been hurt in any of my dangerous reporting work while wearing my boots.&#160; So I consider them lucky.

&#160;

Recently, I had to decide if I should continue to wear my boots.&#160; I had them on my feet during the meltdown at Japan’s Fukushima nuclear power center in March 2011.&#160; I was close to the center when the tsunami hit and damaged the factory. Then, I went to the center to report on the crisis for VOA.

&#160;

I wanted to have the old boots repaired, but I wondered if it was safe to do so.&#160; So I asked for help from the National Atomic Testing Museum.&#160; They told me to talk with Ralf Sudowe, an associate professor of health physics at the University of Nevada-Las Vegas.&#160; He told me that hikers and soldiers often have radioactivity on their shoes.

&#160;

He used a machine called a Geiger counter to measure the radiation level of my boots.&#160; The testing took place almost three years after I wore them at Fukushima.&#160; The counter “clicks” up to 150 times a minute -- the faster the clicking, the more radiation there is.

&#160;


The frequency of the clicks is increasing as I move it over the toe cap of the boots. So there’s definitely something on the tip of these boots -- on the toe cap -- that is more radioactive than the normal background. &#160;If I go to the back of the boot, you don’t hear anything anymore.” &#160;

&#160;

More tests, in a special container, made me feel better about the radiation level of my favorite boots.&#160; Professor Sudowe found that the small amount of radioactivity wouldn’t cause health problems.

&#160;

So I sent them to the place where they were made: the Danner factory in Portland, Oregon.&#160; Several hundred pairs of boots are sent to the factory every month to be repaired.

&#160;

Marci Uselman is the head of the repair department.&#160; She told me people love their boots, even if they are not in good condition.&#160; She said many owners of the boots are emotionally close to them.&#160;

&#160;

“For a police officer, it could be the first pair of boots he had when he began his service. &#160;In the army, they’ve obviously fought and been standing next to their fellow soldiers and it means a lot to them.”

&#160;

I discovered that my boots were among the oldest ever sent to the factory to be repaired. &#160;And, they were among those in the worst condition.

&#160;

Oleg Shyshkin was the Danner employee who worked on my boots. &#160;He began repairing boots as a teenager in Ukraine, where he was born.&#160; His father -- and grandfather before him -- also repaired boots.&#160; They -- and Mr. Shyshkin -- are called “cobblers.”

&#160;

He first tore my boots apart.&#160; This was difficult for me to watch.&#160; Many years of dirt fell onto his work area.&#160; The cobbler then replaced almost every part of the boots -- even the laces!

&#160;

The extremely dry leather of my boots had caused problems. I watched a hole appear when Mr. Shyshkin removed the old stitching.

&#160;

Mr. Shyshkin used tools like pliers and a hammer.&#160; The work he does -- and the kinds of tools he uses -- are the same a cobbler would do and use hundreds of years ago.

&#160;

But, Mr. Shyshkin also used more-recent technology -- an Italian shoe machine.

&#160;

Mr. Shyshkin worked on my boots all day and called the repair a success.&#160; He compared it to medical treatment.

&#160;

“Surgery is done. &#160;The operation is good. &#160;Still alive.”



“How long do you think before they’ll need another surgery?”

&#160;

“How long are you wearing these shoes?”

&#160;

“Already about 23 years.”

&#160;

“I think it’s same.”

&#160;

Workers still manufacture Danner boots as mine were in the early 1990s.&#160; They are hand-made.&#160; In other words, workers do not use machines, except for sewing. Everything is done at the factory, from inspecting the leather to putting on the soles, or bottoms, of the boots. &#160;That is the final step.

&#160;

Most American shoe companies manufacture their products in Asia, where wages are lower. &#160;But some, like Danner, still make some or all of their footwear in America.&#160;

&#160;

Danner meets congressional requirements that their shoes and boots are American-made, using only American products.&#160; But the company’s staff is international. &#160;Only about 12 workers in the factory were born in the United States. There are 87 Vietnamese workers, 14 from Burma, 14 from China and nine Somalis.

&#160;

Danner -- which was formed in 1932 -- is not an American-owned company.&#160; The company was bought in 2012 by a Japanese group of stores called ABC-Mart. &#160;It was at one of that company’s stores in Tokyo that I bought my boots in the early 1990s.

&#160;

For now, the company mostly sells its shoes and boots to American soldiers, police officers, hunters, hikers…and reporters like me.&#160; But the company says it has plans to sell its products to people throughout the world.

&#160;

With my boots on, I’m Steve Herman.

&#160;

Thanks, Steve.

&#160;

That’s our program for today. &#160;

&#160;

I’m Christopher Cruise reporting from VOA Learning English headquarters in Washington. &#160;I’ll be here next week at this same time with another edition of As It Is on The Voice of America.




]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/reporters-steve-herman-danner-lights/1848322.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/reporters-steve-herman-danner-lights/1848322.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>World</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/reporters-steve-herman-danner-lights/1848322.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/53E0113C-8E6A-4026-9ECF-AF10FBAFBEF1_cx0_cy31_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>A Visit to George Washington&#39;s Mount Vernon</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


From VOA Learning English, welcome to This is America.&#160; I’m Steve Ember. Americans are remembering George Washington this month.&#160; February 22nd marks the birthday anniversary of the country’s first president.&#160; Come celebrate the event with us on a visit to Mount Vernon, Washington’s home in Virginia. &#160;



George Washington lived at Mount Vernon for more than 40 years.&#160; The big wooden house is 24 kilometers south of Washington, DC -- the city named in his honor.&#160; But the distance from the city does not stop people from all over the world from visiting the home.&#160; The property can be reached by bicycle, car, bus – even by boat on the Potomac River.

&#160;

George Washington was born on February 11th, 1731.&#160; His birth date moved up a year and 11 days when the Gregorian calendar was accepted.&#160; Before Washington was elected president, he commanded the troops that won the revolutionary war against Britain.&#160; He helped to set up the country now called the United States of America.&#160; Some historians say the nation would not exist if George Washington had never lived.

&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;

Washington helped choose where to build the capital city and an official home for the president.&#160; Yet he is the only president who never lived in the White House.&#160; It was completed after he left office.&#160; Washington lived in New York and later in Philadelphia while he served as president.&#160; But Mount Vernon was always important to him.&#160; And the house he shared with his wife Martha remains an important place in American history.




George Washington’s father, Augustine, started building the house in 1735.&#160; Later the home and farm were named “Mount Vernon.”&#160; At that time, George Washington’s half-brother, Lawrence, had the property.&#160; Lawrence Washington died in 1752.

George Washington took possession of Mount Vernon in 1754.&#160; During the next 45 years, he continually added to it.&#160; The main building grew to its present size of 21 rooms.&#160; He watched over the additions, even while he was away at war. &#160;



Today the house and property still look like a Virginia plantation, a working farm where crops are grown.&#160; But present-day Mount Vernon has been made more meaningful to visitors through many creative displays.&#160; A Hands-On-History Center offers special activities for children aged three to eight. &#160;



Visitors can begin their trip to Mount Vernon with a stop at the Ford Orientation Center.&#160; A film called “We Fight to Be Free” tells about Washington both as a man and as a military leader.&#160; The movie shows the future president commanding British forces during the French and Indian War, which ended in 1763. &#160;




Washington also led a small army across the icy Delaware River on December 25th, 1776.&#160; By that time, the American colonies were fighting for independence from Britain.&#160; Washington’s colonial forces were on their way to fight the Battle of Trenton, in New Jersey.



The colonial forces faced and defeated Hessian troops at Trenton.&#160; The Hessians were fighting on the British side.&#160; Many were captured, and the colonial losses were few.&#160; Winning the battle marked a turning point of the American Revolution. &#160;



The film also tells about Washington’s life in more peaceful times, like his first meeting with his future wife, Martha Custis.&#160; Her first husband had died and left her with four children.&#160; George and Martha Washington took the two youngest and raised them at Mount Vernon as their children.



The public loved George Washington for his service to the country.&#160; Some people wanted him to be president for life.&#160; But Washington said Americans had fought for freedom from such rulers.



He was elected president two times without opposition.&#160; He was offered a third term, but he refused.&#160; Washington said he wanted to return to the life he had led at Mount Vernon before the war.



And that is what he did.&#160; The former president returned to Mount Vernon.&#160; During those last years, he led the life of a rich farmer.&#160; He directed the work of five farms.



George and Martha Washington often invited friends to eat in the dining room at Mount Vernon.&#160; They also provided food and a place to sleep for travelers.&#160; Very few hotels existed then.&#160; So the Washingtons offered a place to stay to about 600 people a year.&#160; Many were strangers.




George Washington was able to enjoy retirement at Mount Vernon for less than three years.&#160; In December of 1799, the former president became sick and died.&#160; He was 67 years old.&#160; Modern doctors believe the cause of death was a severe infection. &#160;

&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;

Many people mourned.&#160; They felt a terrible loss at the death of their revolutionary war hero and first president.&#160; More than 700 speakers throughout the country honored him.&#160; Towns and villages held funeral marches.&#160; Businesses closed for days.&#160; Bells rang and rang.



Now that we know more about George Washington’s life, we will continue with our visit to his Mount Vernon home.&#160; The property contains the family’s main house and smaller buildings.&#160; Visitors also see farming areas, nature paths and – when in season – beautiful flower gardens.&#160; A green hillside leads down to the Potomac River. &#160;

&#160;&#160; &#160;

A guide suggests going into the main house.&#160; It is three floors high.&#160; Washington was responsible for much of its design. &#160;



Today, the mansion has been restored to recapture the past.&#160; Step into the Central Passage, and you find yourself in the world of 1799.&#160; The Central Passage provides an entrance to the house.&#160; But it is more.&#160; It was a place for welcoming and entertaining visitors.&#160; A guide tells us that during summer months, the family gathered near the open doors in the hope of catching some cool air. &#160;



George Washington’s office is on the ground level.&#160; It contains many of his books.&#160; This is the room where Washington planned the farm activities on his land.&#160; It is also where he wrote to other leaders.&#160; One writer called this room, “the center of political intelligence for the new world.”




Another guide leads visitors up some steps.&#160; Mount Vernon has eight bedrooms.&#160; George and Martha Washington needed all these bedrooms for their many visitors.&#160; High above is a cupola -- a small structure with windows on all sides.&#160; Washington designed this so that hot summer air would escape from inside the house.

&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160; &#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;

African slaves were responsible for a great amount of work at Mount Vernon.&#160; More than 300 slaves lived and worked on the property.&#160; Slaves and some paid workers operated George Washington&#39;s five farms.&#160; Together the farms covered more than one-thousand hectares. &#160;

&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;

Other slaves built houses and furniture.&#160; Still others cooked and performed housekeeping duties.&#160; Visitors can see the burial places of slaves at Mount Vernon.&#160; The cemetery holds the remains of slaves and free black people who worked on the property during the 1700s and the first half of the 1800s.&#160; Their final resting places are not marked. &#160;



Many years after the birth of the new country, America’s 16th president Abraham Lincoln signed the Emancipation Proclamation.&#160; The measure ended slavery in southern states, including Virginia.&#160; Lincoln’s action in 1863 was widely criticized as well as praised.&#160; Even in Washington&#39;s time, there was great debate about slavery. &#160;




Washington came to disapprove of slavery as he grew older.&#160; He was the only one of the men known as the Founding Fathers of the country to free his slaves.&#160; He ordered that his slaves be freed after he and his wife died.&#160; Older slaves received payments for years after that. &#160;

&#160;&#160; &#160;

Much is said about George Washington the hero.&#160; But there is also the argument today that not enough is said about Washington the slave owner.



After George and Martha Washington died, Mount Vernon was given to other family members.&#160; By the 1850s, the individual who owned Mount Vernon did not have enough money to keep it in good condition.&#160; He offered to sell it to Virginia or to the federal government.&#160; Both said no.



That is when a private group rescued the home.&#160; The Mount Vernon Ladies’ Association bought the property with money it collected. &#160;

&#160;&#160; &#160; &#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;

If you cannot visit Mount Vernon in person, you can explore it online.&#160; Go to the website, www.mountvernon.org .&#160; It lets you visit the world of a man who helped to build a new nation. And for pictures of Mount Vernon, go to our website: learningenglish.voanews.com.



Our program was written by Jerilyn Watson, and I’m Steve Ember, inviting you to join us again next week for another This Is America program from VOA Learning English.







]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/mount-vernon-george-washington/1849481.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/mount-vernon-george-washington/1849481.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>This Is America</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/mount-vernon-george-washington/1849481.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/933DDE93-D083-4E8B-AF8A-2EDB8427EA84_cx0_cy16_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>UN: One Million Syrian Children Are Refugees</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Hello, and welcome to As It Is from VOA Learning English!&#160; I’m Steve Ember in Washington.&#160;

&#160;

Today on our program, we report on efforts by one group to improve education in Myanmar, also known as Burma.&#160; The government has carried out many reforms since parliamentary elections and the end of military rule in 2011.&#160; But education remains a big issue, especially in rural areas.&#160; Jeri Watson will have more on the story later in the program.&#160;

&#160;

But we begin with a report about Syria.&#160; The United Nations has warned that Syrian children are suffering as a result of the country’s three year-long conflict.&#160; The UN says many of the children have developed emotional problems, are separated from their parents and are not in school.&#160; Milagros Ardin has this report.

&#160;

UN: More Than One Million Syrian Children Are Refugees

&#160;

The United Nations says more than one million Syrian children are registered with its refugee agency, the UNHCR.&#160; Most of them now live in Lebanon and Jordan.

&#160;

These boys and girls may have escaped from the fighting, but they continue to suffer the effects of war.&#160;

&#160;

The UN agency says 75 percent of the 1.1 million children it has registered are under the age of 12.&#160; The agency is urging international donors to increase financial support to refugee families.&#160; It says the money could, in turn, help displaced children.

&#160;

Brian Hansford is a spokesman for the UNHCR.

&#160;

“It illustrates the immense suffering.&#160; We are talking here of psychological distress, withdrawal, anger, loneliness, fractured families and widespread use of child refugees as labor.”

&#160;

The UN report noted efforts to keep Syrian refugee children in school.&#160; But as of September, it said, more than 100,000 of those in Jordan were not attending classes.&#160; And it said twice that number could be out of school in Lebanon.&#160; Disabled children are said to be having an even harder time.

&#160;

Many children, especially boys, are out of school because their families need them for work.&#160; Brian Hansford says the report found that 10 percent of Syrian refugee children in the area are working for a living.&#160; Many work long hours in dangerous conditions.

&#160;

“One child interviewed, he was burned by hot oil in a restaurant, for example.&#160; Another cut his hand while fixing a car mirror, and a third was beaten by the son of his boss.”

&#160;

Refugee babies are also at risk, often lacking necessary documents.&#160; That is because babies born in Syria are not registered if their families fled the country, or if they were born as refugees in Lebanon or Jordan.&#160; Mr.&#160; Hansford says the lack of a birth certificate can create problems for these children later in life.

&#160;

“A birth certificate is a vital document to protect against risks such as statelessness.&#160; And so without a birth certificate, people can have difficulties later enrolling in schools, or getting health care and other services.”

&#160;

The report also found that many Syrian children are growing up without one or both parents.&#160; More than 70,000 Syrian refugee families live without fathers.&#160; And nearly 4,000 refugee children are living without or are separated from both parents.&#160; The UN operates centers for these children in refugee camps.&#160; The centers provide social services while workers try to reunite the youngsters with relatives.&#160;

&#160;

I’m Milagros Ardin.&#160;

&#160;

You are listening to As It Is from VOA Learning English.&#160; I’m Steve Ember.&#160;

&#160;

Burma, also known as Myanmar, is one of the poorest countries in the world.&#160; The United Nations says people there earn an average of about $460 a year.&#160; For more than 20 years, the military ruled the country.&#160; During that time, the international community limited assistance to the country because of its record on human rights.&#160; Myanmar now has an elected government, and international aid has begun to arrive.&#160; But as we hear from Jeri Watson, there are still few resources for education in rural villages.&#160;

&#160;

Building Schools in Burma&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

&#160;


Bob Cornwell and a group called Build a School in Burma are trying to change that.&#160; Three years ago, he was a financial adviser to several foreign governments.&#160; Today, he is building schools in Burma.

&#160;

“We’re really trying to help kids on the margin who wouldn’t otherwise get an education, and kids not having an education is just a recipe for every kind of personal disaster.”

&#160;

He met some of those children in 2010.&#160; He and a friend were travelling from village to village in the northwestern province of Burma.

&#160;

“None of these villages have electricity.&#160; Many of them are not really accessible even by road.&#160; And lots of kids, maybe like five on average per family -- no school.”

&#160;

Bob Cornwell returned to his home in California.&#160; Back home, he learned that the cost of building a primary school in Burma was just $15,000 to $20,000.&#160; So he sold his interest in a financial consulting company that he had started 25 years earlier and returned to Burma.&#160; He looked for villages that would give land and construction help in exchange for a school.&#160;

&#160;

Rick Heizman, an expert on Burmese music, volunteered to help.&#160; He had been working on humanitarian and education projects in Burma for more than 20 years.&#160;

&#160;

Rick Heizman is married to a well-known Burmese harpist, Su Wei.&#160; They live in San Francisco, California, but they return to Burma often to visit the school projects.&#160; Su Wei says the children are excited to learn to read and write.&#160; And she says the parents are happy that their children can get an education without having to leave their village.

&#160;

“The school is inside their village, nearby, so at least they don’t have to worry about taking the kids to the school, faraway places, you know, like that.”

&#160;

Bob Cornwell says the group works with community leaders.

&#160;

“They have a very good connection to the local people.&#160; They understand what the needs are.&#160; So having someone who really understands the local situation is crucial.&#160; They’re on the ground there all the time, so we’ve really focused on those groups.”

&#160;

Bob Cornwell is applying for grants and asking for donations so he can build more schools.&#160; He says spending his retirement years this way has made him happier than he ever imagined he would be.

&#160;

I’m Jeri Watson.

&#160;

As It Is is a production of VOA Learning English.&#160; I’m Steve Ember.&#160; Thanks so much for listening!




]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/one-million-syrian-children-refugess/1850335.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/one-million-syrian-children-refugess/1850335.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>World</category><category>Education</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/one-million-syrian-children-refugess/1850335.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/FB666B5D-AA28-426D-9389-6F1753179512_cx0_cy7_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Do You Have a Broken Heart? A Heart of Stone?</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Now, the VOA Special English program Words and Their Stories.

&#160;

I’m Rich Kleinfeldt with some expressions using the word heart.

&#160;

People believed for a long time that the heart was the center of a person’s emotions.&#160; That is why the word &quot;heart&quot; is used in so many expressions about emotional situations.

&#160;

One such expression is to “lose your heart” to someone. &#160;When that happens, you have fallen in love. &#160;But if the person who won your heart does not love you, then you are sure to have a “broken heart.” &#160;In your pain and sadness, you may decide that the person you loved is “hard-hearted,” and in fact, has a “heart of stone.”

&#160;

You may decide to “pour out your heart” to a friend. &#160;Telling someone about your personal problems can often make you feel better.

&#160;

If your friend does not seem to understand how painful your broken heart is, you may ask her to “have a heart.” &#160;You are asking your friend to show some sympathy for your situation. Your friend “has her heart in the right place” if she says she is sorry, and shows great concern for how you feel.

&#160;

Your friend may, however, warn you not to “wear your heart on your sleeve.” &#160;In other words, do not let everyone see how lovesick you are. &#160;When your heart is on your sleeve you are showing your deepest emotions.

&#160;

If your friend says “my heart bleeds for you,” she means the opposite. &#160;She is a cold-hearted person who does not really care about your situation.

&#160;

In the ever-popular motion picture, “The Wizard of Oz,” the Tin Man seeks a heart. He wanted to feel the emotion of love, and was seeking help from the powerful Wizard of Oz to find a heart.

&#160;

The Cowardly Lion, in the same movie, did have a heart. &#160;But he lacked courage and wanted to ask the Wizard of Oz to give him some. &#160;You could say that the cowardly lion was “chicken-hearted.” &#160;That is another way of describing someone who is not very brave. &#160;A chicken is not noted for its bravery. &#160;Thus, someone who is chicken-hearted does not have much courage.

&#160;

When you are frightened or concerned, your “heart is in your mouth.” &#160;You might say, for example, that your heart was in your mouth when you asked a bank to lend you some money to pay for a new house.

&#160;

If that bank says no to you, do not “lose heart.” &#160;Be strong-hearted. &#160;Sit down with the banker and have a “heart-to-heart” talk: be open and honest about your situation. The bank may have a “change of heart” -- it may agree to lend you the money. Then you could stop worrying and “put your heart at rest.”

&#160;

This VOA Special English program Words and Their Stories was written by Marilyn Christiano.

&#160;

I’m Rich Kleinfeldt.

&#160;




]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/broken-heart-or-heart-of-stone/1849410.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/broken-heart-or-heart-of-stone/1849410.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Words and Their Stories</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/broken-heart-or-heart-of-stone/1849410.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/59763F22-EC3D-410B-ADDC-B2AB97B3903B_cx0_cy10_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>French President&#39;s Visit to US Strengthens Ties</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


From VOA Learning English, this is In the News.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

&#160;

Relations between the United States and France appeared to grow stronger this week after President Francois Hollande visited Washington.&#160; President Barack Obama welcomed the French leader by taking him on Monday to Charlottesville, Virginia.&#160; They visited Monticello, the 18th century house designed and built by Thomas Jefferson, America’s third president.&#160; Jefferson was also one of the writers of the Declaration of Independence and served as America’s representative to France from 1785 to 1789.&#160;

&#160;

President Obama told President Hollande that Monticello is an example of what he called the “incredible history” between the United States and France.&#160; Thomas Jefferson loved France, and was a supporter of the French Revolution.&#160; As Mr. Obama noted, France supported Britain’s North American colonies as they fought for independence.&#160;

&#160;

“All this is signified here at Monticello and our hope in starting our visit in this way is that just as we can extend back through generations to see the links between the United States and France, tomorrow we will have an opportunity to talk about not only our current bonds and alliance, but also ways we can strengthen our cooperation in the future.”

&#160;

President Hollande also spoke to reporters during his visit to Monticello.&#160; He noted how a Frenchman, the Marquis de Lafayette, assisted the colonial forces during the American Revolution.

&#160;

“We were allies in the time of Jefferson and Lafayette, we are indeed still allies today. &#160;We were friends in the time of Jefferson and Lafayette and we will remain friends forever.”

&#160;

President Hollande spent the second day of his state visit in Washington.&#160; He received the traditional ceremonial welcome to the White House before opening talks with President Obama.&#160;

&#160;

Two newspapers, Le Monde and The Washington Post, published an opinion piece written by the two men.&#160; They wrote about a modern relationship marked by expansion.&#160; They said it includes more cooperation in NATO, agreement to remove chemical weapons from Syria and to prevent al-Qaida from gaining more influence in Africa.

&#160;

Tuesday night, the French president was honored at a state dinner.&#160; More than 300 people were invited to the White House.&#160; The dinner guests included top US officials, business leaders and movie stars.&#160;

&#160;

The White House was forced to reprint invitations to the state dinner after Mr. Hollande announced a break-up with his former partner last month. &#160;

&#160;

After the dinner, the French leader flew to California, which is considered the center of American information technology. &#160;There he met with leaders of several IT companies, including Facebook and Google.&#160; At a gathering in San Francisco, Mr. Hollande noted, “It is here in California that the world of tomorrow is being invented.”&#160; He added that “For centuries, France has wanted to change the world. &#160;Together, we can.”&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

&#160;

The French president has invited President Obama to France in June for ceremonies marking the 70th anniversary of the D-Day invasion in Normandy. &#160;That was when Western Allied forces began an effort to free mainland Europe from occupation by Nazi Germany and its allies.&#160; France will also lead a climate conference next year. &#160;Both leaders say they are repeating their promise to lead the world in dealing with climate change. &#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;



And that’s In the News from VOA Learning English.&#160; I’m Steve Ember

.





]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/obama-hollande-french-president-monticello/1851846.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/obama-hollande-french-president-monticello/1851846.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>In the News</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/obama-hollande-french-president-monticello/1851846.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/584FE701-11EA-47E5-A6B2-4629D2BD46BA_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>One Billion Tons of Food Wasted Each Year</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Hello, and welcome to As It Is from VOA Learning English!&#160; I’m Katherine Cole in Washington.&#160;

&#160;

Food waste is a problem around the world, especially in wealthy nations.&#160; Studies estimate that between 30 and 40 percent of the food in wealthy countries is thrown away every year.&#160;

&#160;

At the same time, millions of people in the world do not have enough to eat.&#160; Christopher Cruise will join us today to investigate some of these issues.



Later in the show, Karen Leggett will report on what farmers in the United States are doing to reduce food waste.

&#160;

But first, here is Christopher Cruise.

&#160;

More Than One Billion Tons of Food Wasted Each Year&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; 

&#160;

The United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization says more than a billion tons of food is wasted each year. &#160;Much of that waste happens in wealthy nations, but it happens in developing countries as well.&#160;

&#160;

Even as all this food is being wasted, it is estimated that one billion people are undernourished, and hundreds of millions of people go to sleep hungry each day.

&#160;

Danielle Nierenberg is the co-founder and president of Food Tank, an organization that studies food issues.

&#160;

“A lot of people in the world -- one out of eight people -- are hungry. &#160;And at the same time we have around 1.5 billion people who are obese. &#160;So, that excess has consequences not just on our waistlines, but on the environment, on our food security and a whole range of other factors.”

&#160;

Ms. Nierenberg says much of the food waste in the developing world is caused by poor infrastructure, like bad roads and storage areas that are too small.

&#160;

In wealthy nations, people are to blame because they buy more than they can eat.&#160; Ms. Nierenberg also blames dates that are printed on food containers.&#160; These dates tell buyers and sellers what date the food should be sold or eaten by. &#160;She says these dates cause people to throw away food too soon.

&#160;

VOA spoke with Ms. Nierenberg when she was in Milan, Italy.&#160; She was attending the Barilla Center for Food and Nutrition yearly meeting. &#160;Officials at the meeting released what they call the Milan Protocol. &#160;The document calls on international leaders and policymakers to improve food security.

&#160;

“It not only focuses on food waste, but creating better and more- sustainable agriculture systems, as well as focusing on unhealthy lifestyles and really helping reduce the epidemic of obesity and overweight that is plaguing not just rich countries, but poor countries as well.”

&#160;

Ms. Nierenberg says the amount of food wasted each year shows there is already enough food to feed the planet.

&#160;

“The problem of hunger in the world is not one of not having enough food. &#160;We produce more than enough food for every man, woman and child to eat every day.&#160; Yet, it’s political reasons. &#160;It’s poverty, certainly, that prevents food from getting to people who need it the most.”

&#160;

I’m Christopher Cruise.

&#160;

You are listening to As It Is from VOA Learning English. &#160;I’m Katherine Cole.

&#160;

A lot of people look at the United States as a rich country.&#160; Yet many American farmers are struggling financially.&#160; How do they deal with wasted food and unused crops?&#160; As Karen Leggett reports, some are using social media to help solve the problem.

&#160;

Social Media Helps Farmers

&#160;


The United States Department of Agriculture found that more than half of the small farms in California do not make a profit.

&#160;

One California farm family is using social media in an effort to change the situation and reduce wasted food. &#160;Nick Papadopoulos is general manager of Bloomfield Farms in Sonoma County. &#160;It was difficult for him to watch his employees returning from several weekend farmers’ markets with top quality, unsold produce. &#160;Mr. Papadopoulos said he would find boxes of leafy greens, herbs and carrots left in a storage area. &#160;The vegetables would go bad before the next market day.

&#160;

As a result, Mr. Papadopoulos came up with a plan to offer the food at a low price by advertising it on the farm’s Facebook status page on Sunday nights.

&#160;

“We’re going to put ‘Breaking news!&#160; Crop mob.&#160; Two pallets of Bloomfield Farms’ organic veggies, $150 dollars per pallet.’”&#160;

&#160;

The deals were open to anyone using the social media website. &#160;One week, several homeowners in a neighboring community bought the vegetables.&#160; Another week, the buyers were a group of friends.&#160;

&#160;

Nick Papadopoulos began using social media after he went to work on a farm belonging to his wife’s father. &#160;One night he began thinking about the issue of wasted food when he could not find a place to donate 32 cases of organic broccoli. &#160;He ended up giving some of the food to chickens and using the rest to make fertilizer.

&#160;

“I don’t believe we should let it go to waste. &#160;I believe we should share it, donate it, whatever it takes to get it out there, and if possible - as farmers - we would like to recover a small portion of our cost.”&#160;

&#160;

After his success of using Facebook, Mr. Papadopoulos helped to set up a website called cropmobster.com. &#160;It is a place where people involved with food production, feeding the hungry and those who want to buy locally-grown food can find surplus produce.

&#160;

Have you ever used the Internet to buy or sell crops? &#160;If so, tell us about your experience. &#160;You can leave a message on our Facebook page or visit our website, learningenglish.voanews.com. &#160;

&#160;

I’m Karen Leggett.

&#160;

When you visit our website, click on “Contact Us” to tell us what you want to hear about on a future show.&#160; You can also read, listen to and download our programs.&#160; You will also find podcasts, captioned videos and lessons to test your English skills.



That’s our program for today.&#160; I&#39;m Katherine Cole.&#160; Thanks so much for listening!&#160; Join us again tomorrow for another As It Is from VOA Learning English.&#160;

&#160;

And, for the latest world news, be sure to listen to VOA at the top of the hour, Universal Time.




]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/one-billion-tons-food-wasted-/1848583.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/one-billion-tons-food-wasted-/1848583.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>World</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/one-billion-tons-food-wasted-/1848583.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/9A6FF1D7-03E1-4F79-BF55-253BCF1E4ADB_cx0_cy5_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Valentine&#39;s Day: A History of the Day of Love</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Welcome to American Mosaic in VOA Learning English. I&#39;m June Simms. On the show today we explore the history of Valentine&#39;s Day.



Happy Valentine’s Day!&#160; Americans celebrate the holiday each year on February fourteenth.&#160; So do candy companies, jewelry stores and people selling flowers.&#160; Marsha James tells us more about Valentine’s Day in the United States.




Valentine’s Day is for lovers. It is a good day to ask your boyfriend or girlfriend to marry you.&#160; It is also a popular day for marriage ceremonies.



But, other couples might celebrate with dinner at a nice restaurant.



The holiday is named for Saint Valentine.&#160; He was an early Christian clergyman who was said to have helped young lovers.&#160; Valentine was executed for his Christian beliefs on February fourteenth, more than one thousand seven hundred years ago.&#160; But the day that has his name is even older than that.

&#160;

The ancient Romans celebrated a holiday for lovers more than two thousand years ago.&#160; As part of the celebration, each girl reportedly wrote her name on a piece of paper and put it in a large container.&#160; Each boy reached into the container and pulled out the name of a girl.&#160; That girl became his girlfriend for a year.

&#160;

Lovers still put their names on pieces of paper on Valentine’s Day.&#160; They send each other cards that express their love.&#160; Sometimes they send other gifts, too, like jewelry… or flowers… or candy…or all three!&#160;

&#160;

So Valentine’s Day is big business in America. The National Retail Federation is a trade group. The federation represents retail stores in the United States and other countries. It expects the average American to spend about $134 for Valentine’s Day this year. That is up about three dollars from 2013. The group also says men will spend about twice as much on their partners as women will. And it says it expects total spending for Valentine’s Day in the United States to reach about $17.3 billion.



I&#39;m June Simms. Join us again next week for American Mosaic from VOA Learning English.







]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/valentine-love-february14-candy-hearts-chocolate/1850316.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/valentine-love-february14-candy-hearts-chocolate/1850316.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>USA</category><category>American Mosaic</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/valentine-love-february14-candy-hearts-chocolate/1850316.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/B9B10CD4-AE4B-4A1A-884F-58E407E5967E_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>Supporters Call on Britain to Return Jailed Governor to Nigeria</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Welcome back to the program. I’m Caty Weaver.

&#160;

In January, Britain and Nigeria signed a prisoner exchange agreement.&#160; Now, Nigerians are questioning what will happen with a well-known Nigerian politician currently in a British jail. If the former Delta state governor returns to Nigeria will he be loved or hated? Will he be jailed or freed?

&#160;

Then we talk about the growing popularity of games of Chance among Liberian youth.&#160; Some say the activity could be damaging to the country.



James Ibori: Hero or Criminal in Nigeria?

&#160;

Britain is preparing to send some Nigerians jailed in the country back to Nigeria. British officials say any Nigerian serving a sentence of more than 12 months will be sent home, if both governments agree to the prisoner exchange.

&#160;

One of the prisoners could be James Ibori, a popular former governor.&#160; He is serving 13 years for corruption.&#160; Unlike other prisoners, Ibori may be treated like a hero if he comes home.&#160;

&#160;

Two years ago, a court in London sentenced James Ibori to 13 years in a British prison.&#160; He was earlier accused of stealing $250 million in public money from the Nigerian government.&#160; Before that, he was accused two times of corruption in Nigeria.&#160; But he was never found guilty of any crime.

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Ibori supporters say the accusations and the British court ruling were moves by politicians seeking to crush Ibori’s support.&#160; They say they would welcome him home.&#160;

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Davidson Okparamidevi worked on Ibori’s two successful campaigns for governor.&#160; He says Ibori’s popularity in Delta State is indisputable.

&#160;

“Ibori became so popular because of his clear-cut achievements that have impacted positively on the lives of the entire Deltans. The list of his achievements as impacted on the people is inexhaustible.”

&#160;

He says Ibori built roads, bridges and hospitals.&#160; He says President Goodluck Jonathan would do well to get Ibori back home and pardon him.&#160; The president is expected to seek re-election in 2015.

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

In recent months, Mr. Jonathan’s ruling People’s Democratic Party has lost several top officials, including five state governors.&#160; Rebellion in the north and poverty around the nation has also damaged the president’s popularity.

&#160;

Again Davidson Okparamidevi.

&#160;

“So if Ibori shows up it will be a boost.&#160; A real boost to Goodluck Jonathan to office.”&#160;&#160;

&#160;

But other Nigerians are not so sure. &#160;Onyiye Gandhi is a lawyer in the oil-rich but poor city of Warri in Delta state.&#160; He says that Ibori used money from oil to pay back his followers and buy loyalty.

&#160;

“Giving him freedom would indict Jonathan and confirm the allegations, very widespread now among Nigerians, that his government is massively corrupt, and pampers corruption.”

&#160;

The British-Nigerian prisoner exchange was announced in early January.&#160; Under the proposal, hundreds of Nigerians in British prisons could be sent home, as well as one British citizen in Nigeria.

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Amnesty International says it is “extremely concerned” that poor conditions in Nigerian prisons could make the exchange inhumane.&#160;

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Observers in Nigeria say if James Ibori is sent home but not freed, there is no way he will serve the rest of his sentence in a dirty jail cell.&#160;

&#160;

You are listening to As It Is from VOA Learning English.

&#160;

Betting for a Living in Liberia

&#160;

Several sports betting companies have set up operations in Liberia.&#160; Young people who are unemployed gather at these betting parlors in hopes of winning money on things like televised football matches.&#160; Some say betting can provide the money they need -- just like having a good-paying job.&#160; But others are not so sure these games of chance are a good idea. Christopher Cruise has the story.




At a betting parlor in Monrovia, a group of young men place their bets on a football match.&#160; Then they wait for the results on television.&#160;

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Harris Kokeh is 37 years old. &#160;He completed a college degree program, but could not find a job.&#160; He says he started betting and is making a living from it.

&#160;

“I’ve really been living by it.&#160; It has been helping me a lot.&#160; The last time I won about 700 United States dollars.&#160; It was a great help to me.”

&#160;

But not everyone is sure betting is a good thing.&#160; Harrison Myers is about the same age as Harris Kokeh.&#160; He says students are playing games of chance instead of going to school.

&#160;

“This gambling thing is bad for our society. Our youth are not going to school any longer. They spend the entire day at the gambling center.”

&#160;

Back at the betting parlor, Theo Varney says he does not have much choice.&#160; He is out of work, and has two children.

&#160;

“We have no much facility to take care of our affairs, so what do you expect? We are not betting because we want to bet. We are betting because we want to make our living.”

&#160;

Randall Kaybee works for a betting company named Winner’s Incorporated.&#160; He says the business employs young people across the country, creating hundreds of jobs.

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

He also says betting companies are changing people’s lives for just a few Liberian dollars per bet.&#160;

&#160;

“As you just enter my office, as you can see from this evidence. This is a ticket. Somebody bet 50 LD (Liberian dollars) and winning 233,275 Liberian dollars.”

&#160;

One American dollar is worth about 86 Liberian dollars.

Winner’s Incorporated says more than 7,000 Liberians bet each week at its parlors around the country.&#160; And there are 300 to 400 weekly winners.

&#160;

The Liberian government controls all legal betting in the country.&#160; Liberian officials say the betting shops “help promote government poverty reduction strategy.”&#160;

&#160;

I’m Christopher Cruise.

&#160;

And that’s As It Is for today.&#160; I’m Caty Weaver.

&#160;

We want to know what you want to hear about on As It Is. Send an email to learningenglish@voanews.com.&#160; You can also leave a message on our website: learningenglish.voanews.com.

&#160;

Thanks for joining us.


]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/nigeria-delta--ibori-britain-liberia-betting-youth/1851075.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/nigeria-delta--ibori-britain-liberia-betting-youth/1851075.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 21:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>World</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/nigeria-delta--ibori-britain-liberia-betting-youth/1851075.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/C304376A-2618-4E95-B83E-F81E7CEFAD73_cx0_cy10_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>South Africans Find a New Way to Live</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


Hello and welcome back.&#160; I’m Jim Tedder in Washington.&#160;



Today we travel to South Africa to see how the other guy lives.&#160; We will introduce you to a man who has some new ideas about living in the big city.&#160; Our second item is for the birds.&#160; Actually it is about the birds, and how they have known something for thousands of years that we are just learning.

&#160;

As It Is …a radio and Internet program to help you learn and improve your American English…is coming your way …from VOA.

&#160;

Ten year ago, the central downtown business area of Johannesburg, South Africa, looked as if it had seen much better days.&#160; Many buildings stood empty.&#160;&#160; Normal city services had stopped operating.&#160; But these days in the area known as CDB, things are different.&#160;

&#160;

Anderson Street is a main connector in downtown Johannesburg.&#160; Very near that street, Dirk Bahmann walks through a building’s entrance area.&#160; He steps into the elevator and rides up to the fourth level.



He opens a door at the end of the hall and enters a space planned for both work and home living.&#160; The area has become his personal design and building project since he bought the apartment six years ago.

&#160;

Mr. Bahmann is an architect and artist who grew up in the suburbs north of Johannesburg.&#160; But he says urban living connects him better to the community than living in towns on the edges of cities.

&#160;

&#160;“For me, living in the city was a means to kind of connect with people in an everyday, ordinary way without it having to be pretentious, and that you feel part and belong to something.&quot;



Over the last few years, developers have retaken ownership of many buildings.&#160; Crime has decreased.&#160; Middle- and upper-class home buyers have started to take an interest in the area.

&#160;

Mr. Bahmann designed and built his own modern apartment.&#160; It is both home and office.&#160; It uses movable furniture to make the space seem as large as possible.&#160; But he says there is one problem with living in the city.

&#160;

&quot;The only thing I miss is getting a full night&#39;s sleep. &#160;&#160;I&#39;m very sensitive to noise, so I always wake up when someone is walking down the road and shouting, or people who hoot when they want to get into the building.&quot;

&#160;

He says except for lack of sleep, the area provides easy living.&#160;&#160; He can buy food, eat at restaurants, and get all his art materials within minutes from home.

&#160;

Just outside the downtown area is Johannesburg&#39;s Brixton neighborhood. Small houses there are built close to the ground.&#160; Homeless people often sleep on steps and porches and under building extensions that protect them the rain and the hot sun.

&#160;

Some people see danger in Brixton.&#160; But architect Thomas Chapman sees something else.&#160; He says he sees the possibility of apartment living, or what is called loft living.&#160;&#160; Mr. Chapman says the area has great promise to develop and increase its population.

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;

&quot;That&#39;s why we&#39;re choosing to act here, because I don&#39;t think it&#39;s been fully realized, the potential here for what we call loft living or apartment living.”



Mr. Chapman is with a group called Local Studio.&#160; He and his partners are working on a building with eight apartment units, a coffee shop and a new office space for their own business.&#160;

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Mr. Chapman says developers are leading the efforts to redevelop CDB.&#160; But he says the city attracted their interest.&#160; He said, for example, that the city invested in such community basics as pavement – hard roads and sidewalks.&#160;

&#160;

&quot;The truth is that management has gotten better and crime has gotten less. I strongly think it&#39;s an urban management issue, and the city has made strides.&quot;

&#160;

Still, developers are taking private responsibility for some issues. Mr. Chapman pointed to the successful development of Maboneng. Developers there have hired full-time security guards.&#160; They also have invested in street lighting and waste management.

&#160;

Mr. Chapman says his development will likely need some of those same investments.&#160;&#160; And he says they usually provide a return.&#160; The architect says there is a great chance for Johannesburg&#39;s city neighborhoods to grow and compete with traditional living in suburbs.&#160;

&#160;

He says that as a designer of cities, he believes that is where the future lies.

&#160;

&#160;

“V” Is For Energy Efficiency

&#160;

No matter where people are making new homes and offices, saving energy is important.&#160; For us humans, the goal can be difficult.&#160; But for some of our feathered friends, being energy efficient comes naturally.&#160; Just take a look up there.

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

Scientists at Britain’s Royal Veterinary College in London may have solved a mystery that has puzzled us for years.&#160; Why do flocks of birds often fly in a formation that looks similar to the letter “V”? The answer is, they say, because it saves energy.

&#160;

This is how it works.&#160; Many drivers know that being behind a large truck can save you gasoline.&#160; That is because the truck is pushing a lot of air around it.&#160; The car faces less resistance because a partial vacuum – an empty space – is created behind it.




Steven Portugal, a researcher at the Royal Veterinary College, says birds knew that long ago.&#160; The scientific team studied Northern Bald Ibises.&#160; They placed small devices on the back of each bird.&#160; One of the devices, a kind of GPS, recorded the flight plan it followed.



The other device documented the birds’ wing movements.&#160; The readings showed that the birds could use the rising stream of air created by the tip - the edge of the wing - of the bird flying in front of it.

&#160;

Mr. Portugal said it was already known from earlier research that birds could be helped to save their energy by flying in V-formation.&#160; But he said his team showed the way the upward stream of air could be put to work.&#160;

&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;

“Scientists had predicted that birds could take advantage of this by flying in a V-formation shape.&#160; But actually what no one had been able to do previously was to understand the mechanism by which that upwash could be captured.”

&#160;

The Austrian conservation group Waldarappteam and its special aircraft helped the British scientists.&#160; With that help they were able to follow the birds on their migration to Italy.

&#160;&#160;

The GPS navigation devices recorded in real time the position and speed of each bird within the flock.&#160; The other devices, the accelerometers, recorded how fast and hard each bird flapped its wings back and forth.&#160; The scientists recreated the birds’ movements in a computer.

&#160;

Jim Usherwood is a Royal Veterinary College professor.&#160;&#160; He says each bird was very effective in reacting and responding to the movement of the bird just in front of it.

&#160;

“If you can position yourself in the right bit of upwards air, then you can get some kind of benefit.”

&#160;

Scientists now plan to study how the birds decide which bird will lead the flock on yearly migrations across Europe.

&#160;

My, how time flies when you are having fun!&#160; Get it?&#160; Flies?&#160; Birds?&#160; Oh, well.&#160;



Thank you for spending some time with us.&#160; Remember, more Learning English Programs are just seconds away.&#160;&#160; And world news follows at the beginning of the hour.&#160;



I’m Jim Tedder in Washington.&#160; We’ll see you later!






]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/houses-offices-birds-energy/1843691.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/houses-offices-birds-energy/1843691.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>World</category><category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/houses-offices-birds-energy/1843691.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/C6E553F6-A8EC-467E-A70F-280515CBBF6E_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>John Quincy Adams, a Man Raised to Serve His Country</title>
            <description><![CDATA[


From VOA Learning English, welcome to The Making of a Nation, our weekly program of American history for people learning English. I’m Steve Ember.



John Quincy Adams was sworn in as president of the United States on March 4, 1825. A big crowd came to the Capitol building for the ceremony. All the leaders of government were there: senators, congressmen, Supreme Court justices and James Monroe. Monroe’s two terms as president were ending.



President-elect Adams focused his inaugural address on unity. Adams said the Constitution and the representative democracy of the United States had proved a success. The nation was free and strong and stretched across the continent, from the Atlantic Ocean to the Pacific.



He noted that during the past 10 years, political party differences had eased. So now, he said, it was time for the people to settle their differences and make a truly national government.



Adams closed his speech by recognizing that he was a minority president. No candidate had received a majority of electoral votes. So the House of Representatives had to make the decision. The House chose Adams as the next president. He told the crowd gathered at the Capitol that he needed the help of everyone in the years to come.



Presidents-elect used to give their inaugural address before their swearing in. So, after his speech, John Quincy Adams took the oath of office that made him the sixth president of the United States.



His father was John Adams, the second president. John Quincy’s mother, Abigail, made sure he received an excellent education.



Historian Harlow Giles Unger wrote a biography of John Quincy Adams – “Quinzy” incidentally is how the family pronounced it. The historian tells this story about Abigail Adams and her son in 1775 in Massachusetts during the Revolutionary War.



“When her first-born son John, John Quincy, was seven, they heard the cannon fire in the distance and they went up to the top of the hill behind their farm house and could look across Boston Harbor and see the Battle of Bunker Hill. And she took her boy by the hand and they went back down to the house and she started melting down the family pewter, with John Quincy helping her, and making musket balls for the American revolutionary troops.”



Abigail and John Adams were strong patriots. They were one of the founding families of America. Harlow Giles Unger says Abigail Adams raised John Quincy to serve his country.




“She told her son that if you do not grow up to be a great leader of this country, it will be because of your own laziness and obstinacy. She and her husband, John Adams, at that point decided to raise their son to be the president of the United States.”



As a boy, John Quincy Adams learned to speak at least four languages and read Greek and Latin. He studied Shakespeare’s plays. He traveled in Europe. He worked with his father in American consulates and embassies.



He graduated from Harvard and was working as a lawyer by the age of 23.



“He was a brilliant, brilliant young boy and man.”



For about 25 years, Adams held mostly appointed jobs. He was ambassador to the Netherlands, Germany, Russia and Britain. He helped lead the negotiations that ended the War of 1812 between Britain and the United States. And he served eight years as secretary of state.



Adams spent most of his career working in public service. Harlow Giles Unger says he could be impatient, especially with lawmakers.



“He despised most of the politicians he met in Congress because he found them to be ignorant and self-serving, with no sense of patriotism and sense of obligation to the nation.”



John Quincy Adams did not care for political battles. When he became president, he tried to bring his political opponents and the different parts of the country together in his cabinet. His opponents, however, refused to serve. And, although his cabinet included southerners, he did not really have the support of the South.



In his first message to Congress, President Adams described his ideas about the national government. The chief purpose of the government, he said, was to improve the lives of the people it governed. To do this, he offered a national program of building roads and canals. He also proposed a national university and a national scientific center.



Adams said Congress should not be limited only to making laws to improve the nation&#39;s economic life. He said it should make laws to improve the arts and sciences, too.



Many people of the West and South did not believe that the Constitution gave the federal government the power to do all these things. They believed that these powers belonged to the states. Their representatives in Congress rejected Adams’ proposals.



Harlow Giles Unger says some of the disagreements during Adams’ presidency helped start the American Civil War more than 30 years later, in 1861.



“The country was now splitting. The South, most of the South, had never accepted the Constitution as such. The Constitution did away with state sovereignty, but many Americans never accepted that, and especially in the South.”



The political picture in the United States began to change during the administration of John Quincy Adams. His opponents won control of both houses of Congress in the elections of 1826.



Adams’ opponents called themselves Democrats. They supported Andrew Jackson and wanted him to win the next presidential election.



Democrats needed the support of both the West and the South to elect Jackson. So they proposed a bill that appeared to help the West.



The bill involved import taxes. A number of western states wanted duties on industrial goods imported from other countries. The purpose was to protect their own industries.



Southern states, however, opposed the import duties. They produced no industrial goods that needed protection. They argued that the Constitution did not give the government in Washington the right to approve such taxes.



The Democrats expected Congress to defeat the bill they proposed. They thought the West would be grateful that the Democrats had tried to help them. And the South would be happy that there would be no import taxes.



But to the Democrats&#39; surprise, many congressmen from the Northeast joined with lawmakers from the West to support the bill. They did so even though the bill would harm industries in the Northeast. The Northerners wanted to keep the idea of protective trade taxes alive.



The bill passed in both the House of Representatives and the Senate. This left President Adams with a difficult decision. Should he sign it into law? Or should he veto it?



If he signed the bill, it would show he believed that the Constitution allowed protective duties. That decision would create even more opposition to him in the South. If he vetoed it, then he would lose support in the West and Northeast. Adams signed the bill. But he made clear that Congress was fully responsible for it.



Democrats in Congress made other attempts to weaken support for Adams. For example, they claimed that he was misusing government money. They tried to show that he, and his father before him, had become rich from government service.



Others accused him of giving government jobs to his supporters. This charge was false. Top administration officials had urged Adams to give government jobs only to men who were loyal to him. But Adams had refused. He felt that as long as someone had done nothing wrong, he should continue in his job.



During his four years as president, Adams removed 12 people from government jobs. In each case, the person had failed to do his work or had done something criminal.



Adams often gave jobs to people who did not support him politically. He believed it was wrong to give a person a job just for political reasons. Many of Adams&#39; supporters could not understand. They had worked hard to get him elected. Their support for him cooled.



Historian Harlow Giles Unger says John Quincy Adams was never able to meet the high expectations many had for him.&#160;



“His presidency was a complete failure. He was able to accomplish nothing.”



The political battle between Adams&#39; Republican Party and Jackson&#39;s Democrats remained bitter. Perhaps the worst fighting took place in the press. Each side had its own newspaper for support. The Daily National Journal supported the administration. The United States Telegraph supported Andrew Jackson.



At first, the pro-administration newspaper called for national unity and an end to personal attacks. Then things changed. The paper had to defend against charges of political wrongdoing within Adams’ party. It needed to turn readers away from these problems. So it printed a pamphlet that had been used against Andrew Jackson during an election campaign.



The pamphlet accused Jackson of many bad things. The most damaging part involved the wife of another man. That will be our story next week. &#160;



I’m Steve Ember, inviting you to join us next time for The Making of a Nation — American history from VOA Learning English.








]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/john-quincy-adams-abigail-adams-andrew-jackson/1739060.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/john-quincy-adams-abigail-adams-andrew-jackson/1739060.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 23:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>The Making of a Nation</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/john-quincy-adams-abigail-adams-andrew-jackson/1739060.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/02F35BC0-3054-45D4-B540-D66B5DB4EBF5_cx0_cy6_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        <item>
            <title>A Turkish Law Raises Questions About Government and the Internet</title>
            <description><![CDATA[Also, the Committee to Protect Journalists has added cyberspace to its list of places where media freedom is at risk | As It Is]]></description>
            <link>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/turkey-law-internet-government-journalist/1849463.html</link> 
            <guid>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/turkey-law-internet-government-journalist/1849463.html</guid>            
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 00:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>As It Is</category><comments>http://learningenglish.voanews.com/content/turkey-law-internet-government-journalist/1849463.html#relatedInfoContainer</comments><enclosure url="http://gdb.voanews.com/B819F912-C08A-4813-9084-1DCEEA801062_cx0_cy0_cw0_w800_r1.jpg" length="3123" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>   
        </channel></rss>